Six years ago
The Explorers' Association,
or the Association for short,
is the treasure hunters' headquarters.
Maybe we shouldn't do this.
But we haven't even gone in!
Besides, you're the one who said
we should aim for the capital!
Yeah.
I keep telling you.
While you guys might be fine,
I'm just going to drag you all down.
I should just go home.
Jeez. You're overthinking it.
I'll open it.
Luke, no fair!
Hey!
Which one of you here is the best swordsman?
My name is Luke Sykol.
I am the greatest swordsman in the world!
Luke, I told you.
It's not fair that you're stealing the show!
Early bird gets the worm.
I'm Liz Smart, the greatest thief in the world.
Wai—
We're here today to register
as treasure hunters.
You better be grateful!
The truly strong need not rely on a weapon!
Those are the words of our leader, Krai!
Which means that because
I fight with a mere wooden sword,
I'm the strongest in the world!
Uh, huh... That's great for you.
I feel like I'm about to puke,
so please stop mentioning me.
Excuse me, but do you get
other crazy newbies like us?
Once in a blue moon...
Well, please register your
party's name and crest.
Our party's name?
Now that you mention it,
we've never thought about it.
Your party's name and crest will come
to represent the core values of your party.
So don't just pick something
random. Take your time.
I got it.
I'll show you what you get
for making me the leader.
With a name like this, nobody
would ever think we're strong.
Done.
Our party's name is "Grieving Souls."
For our crest, we'll go
with this skullish thing.
Talk about bad taste.
Aren't we a party of heroes?
With a name like that,
we run the risk of people thinking
we're an antisocial party...
I want something cuter!
Agreed.
If we don't use this name,
I just can't get motivated.
Looks like I failed as your leader.
Guess I have no choice but to
leave the party and cheer you—
You've got great taste, actually!
On second thought, it's really cool!
As long as we do good deeds, it's fine!
Krai, you're the best!
Agreed.
Is this your party name, then?
Uh, yes.
This, please.
That's how our party,
Grieving Souls, was born.
We are now in the golden age
of the treasure hunters!
Amid the sparkling talent on
display in the capital of Zebrudia,
there was one man who stood
out amongst all others!
His name is Krai Andrey.
This is an epic tale
full of glory and agony
of how he became renowned
for being the leader
of the strongest party he founded
with his childhood friends,
and also the master of the strongest clan!
So what does "Grieving Souls" even mean?
You didn't know?
Something like lamenting spirits.
Right.
Episode 02
I Want to Leave It to Tino and Take It Easy
"I Want to Leave It to Tino
and Take It Easy."
Let This Grieving Soul Retire
I-I could only half believe
it yesterday, but...
Are you really the clan master of Steps?
If I may humbly say so, Great Greg.
So you're Thousand Tricks?
Thousand Tricks?
The level 8?!
Now that you understand how great
our Master is, hurry up and get on your knees.
Tino, let's not be threatening, okay?
Thousand Tricks was the
second name given to me
as the leader of the Grievers.
Hunters who achieve a
certain prestige and status
are given special names by the Association
and become revered almost like celebrities.
For a hunter, there is no higher praise.
Wait, hold up!
There is no way you're Thousand
Tricks, the strongest in the capital!
Get out of here!
You look like you never train!
It's sad that you can't recognize
Master's strength.
You're wasting 90% of your life.
Tino, let's be quiet now, okay?
Master, there's no way I can work with him.
Guys who are all talk are the worst!
You just perfectly described me.
Who said I'm the strongest
in the capital, anyway?
The strongest in the capital!
I have a rough idea...
I figure you heard the rough
details, so what do you think?
Will the three of you help
Tino out with this job?
What a joke.
Why should I listen to you?
Level 8, my ass!
You idiot! Do you know
who you're picking a fight with?
Who are you calling an idiot?
How can this be the leader of the strongest
party that everybody always talks about?!
I won't accept it!
He's level 8!
And I'm level 4!
Fine. We'll give up on young Gilbert, then.
You'll help out, right, Great Greg?
Y-Yes.
I don't mind, but...
What about you, Rhuda?
I figured this would be perfect, since you
wanted to go to the White Wolf's Den.
Well, this isn't really
something I wanted, but...
Wait, what do you mean,
give up on me?
I won't help out, then!
Yeah, it's unfortunate, but what can we do?
Tino, if you need more help,
just take someone else from the clan.
Master, please come with us...
I. Don't. Want. To.
Right, then.
Great Greg and Rhuda, I'm counting on you.
I challenge you!
Thousand Tricks, I challenge you!
If I lose, I'll go along.
What do you say?!
I'm not going to listen to
anyone weaker than me!
Then you won't be fighting me,
but the party leader, Tino.
Please leave it to me.
You were atrociously rude
toward Master.
I, Tino Shade, will rain divine
punishment down upon you!
Master, look!
This is the flexibility I learned
directly from my teacher!
I can assume any position I need.
Yeah, sure.
I have no idea what you're talking
about, but that's great.
I was careless during the ring incident,
but I'm going all in today!
Thousand Tricks, once I
beat her, you're next.
Yeah, no. Why do I have to fight?
Oh, by the way, she's also level 4.
What?!
Just warning you.
Compared to Master, I'm garbage.
But there's no way that
I could lose this fight.
I'll hold back so I don't kill you.
Is she really going to be okay?
In a face-to-face battle,
a thief won't last a second.
He's not wrong...
While they're the same level,
since Tino gained them solo,
she's probably better than him.
And she's had plenty of
experience fighting humans.
The only problem is that relic,
the Purgatorial Sword.
Depending on its abilities,
it could easily tip the scales in his favor.
Don't underestimate me.
I don't need a weapon
against an unarmed female!
Is he stupid?
A swordsman throwing away his sword?
Well, I guess now it comes
down to their own ability.
Once I win, I'll go get
ice cream with Master.
I didn't promise that.
I want to go get ice cream!
Ice cream with Master!
Fine.
Once the job is done.
Yay!
Master, did you see that?
Divine punishment!
Not so fast!
It's not over yet!
I think you know,
but I was holding back.
If you don't want more pain,
never talk back to Master again.
You will worship him as a god and
pray to him three times a day.
You will regularly bring me tributes.
I'll pass them on to Master.
Do you...
ever shut up?!
Did you see that, Master?!
You've helped me grow so much.
Yeah, I've done
absolutely nothing, though.
So this is how strong the Steps are...
Even without weapons...
Master, how did you like
my variety of moves?
I...
can still go—
I was born to become a hunter.
I took up the sword as a kid and
quickly surpassed even the adults.
I grew up and came to the capital.
There, I formed a party with some others
and cleared multiple treasure vaults.
I was proud of how far
I had come so quickly.
Nobody can defeat me.
I am the strongest.
I am...
Hey.
If you want to keep going,
you should use that sword.
As if...
What foolish pride.
It's all for nothing if you die.
She's right.
In a real fight, I would have
been long dead.
Being forced to see
how much weaker I am...
is...
So, hey. You left your party because the difference
in power between you
and the others was too great, right?
How... did you know?
The same thing happened in my party.
Well, in our case, nobody was abandoned.
Wouldn't let me be abandoned, I should say.
Grieving Souls is a group of elites who
stand out even here in the capital.
So that means he's been showing
mercy to people like that?
The level 8, Thousand Tricks.
Nobody knows his true nature.
The man is like a phantom.
Aha.
Elemental damage and improved attack range.
It's a simple but good sword.
You should treat it well.
Th-This can't be happening.
He handled the Purgatorial
Sword with such ease.
Even I haven't managed this kind of flame...
And he didn't even hold the hilt...
This can't be!
This cannot be.
You... monster.
Mana material is said to be the
core substance of this world,
and while it is everywhere, it
cannot be seen with the naked eye.
And treasure vaults
are a phenomenon where ley lines and
other forces condense mana material,
thereby manifesting limited
alternate worlds based
on memories extracted from
the core of the world.
Even though the rules governing this
are studied across many lands,
they are still not entirely understood.
The White Wolf's Den is one
of these treasure vaults.
The site was originally inhabited by wolf
monsters called Silver Moons,
but they were eradicated due to
uncontrolled hunting of their fur.
Soon after, the treasure vault appeared there
as well as a blood-soaked wolf phantom.
Yeah, nope.
That's too scary.
A treasure vault that's a vengeful
reflection of history is too much.
You're the one who made them go there.
The vault is only level 3,
and there's four of them.
They'll be fine.
And Tino's quite level-headed, too.
But thanks for giving me that
information on young Gilbert.
He was quite shocked when I "guessed"
the reason for why he'd left his party.
I'm glad I could be of assistance.
Speaking of,
I heard you made quite a spectacle
with a relic in the training hall?
Yeah, it was a straightforward one.
Those I can control immediately.
Even young Gilbert can use it a little
bit without knowing anything.
Relics are so great.
The infinite variety of shapes and
uses makes them so fun to collect.
Even I can perform miracle-like
things with them.
That Purgatorial Sword is
really something, too.
I wonder if he'd sell it to me?
I might find even more effects if I
could play around with it some more.
I'm against wasteful spending.
You have many relics like it already.
Th-That's not true!
They're totally different.
Each relic has its own personality,
and though they may look similar,
they all tick a bit differently.
R-Rings are nice, right?
There are Shooting Rings,
Safety Rings for protection,
and the Owl's Eye for seeing in the dark.
Krai, even though the Grievers
have a considerable income,
you're going to have to
rein it in a little.
I heard you've even taken loans from Sitri.
The Grievers' profits are split evenly amongst
its members, regardless of contribution.
Therefore, although I do nothing,
I also get loads of money.
Oh, I forgot to get my relics charged.
Sorry to ask out of the blue.
I'm not about to go out on a hunt,
so I don't mind doing this one.
Right.
You're always taking care of us, too.
Thanks so much.
Well, Eva and Ark are the
ones who are taking care...
That reminds me, Master,
have you heard?
They say a wayward phantom
appeared on a road up north.
Destroyed an entire guarded caravan.
Really? That's unsettling.
There were three level 3 guards.
Since they still got defeated, it
must have been one strong phantom.
The Knights of the Third Order are now
recruiting for an extermination party.
Hmm.
Witnesses say the phantom had a wolf's form.
The place isn't far from
the White Wolf's Den,
so I guess it came from there.
The White Wolf's Den?
Maybe there was a mass spawning of phantoms.
The treasure vault must be crawling
with wolves right about now.
Here you go, all charged.
Hold on. This is all just speculation.
I'm sure the White Wolf's
Den has nothing to do with it.
And Tino's really strong.
Young Gilbert went along, too.
Great Greg also has some experience.
But... Speaking of the White Wolf's Den,
there've been reports of its
phantoms becoming stronger lately.
I think they were even talking
about changing its level.
That's news to me!
Anyway, that's a dangerous area right now.
That Rudolph Davout's party went
missing some days back, too.
Oh, you mean that
famous level 5 lancer?
Level 5?
The ones in need of rescue are Rudolph
Davout and five other level 5 hunters.
I didn't read any of this...
Is something wrong, Master?
Oh, uh... The thing is,
I just sent Tino off to
the White Wolf's Den.
Y-You sent Tino, a level 4, into a treasure vault
where a level 5 party went missing?
Y-You're as tough as always, huh, Master?
It'll be good practice
for her, so no worries.
I also sent three independent
hunters with her.
Th-This is already a difficult mission,
and you sent her with some ad-hoc party?
So these must be the Thousand Trials...
That's what made the Grievers the top party.
I-I remembered some urgent business.
Thanks for the charge!
Later.
It's fine. It's fine.
Young Gilbert is quite capable.
As long as he has the Purgatorial Sword...
He did charge it after that, right?
What's this strange feeling?
We haven't even gotten to
the treasure vault yet.
This is why I wrote a will.
Since Master delegated this to me,
it won't be an easy mission.
I've got no intention of dying,
but I want to be prepared.
So Krai knew that there was something
going on at the White Wolf's Den,
and that's why he sent us here?
That's right.
And this party's composition
isn't random, either.
It's all according to Master's plan.
I really don't think that's true.
We all met for the first time yesterday.
That's right.
I only agreed to come along with you
because I happened to be free...
Wait, Thousand Tricks even knew the
reason I had quit my other party.
Master has extensive knowledge
about the hunters in the capital
and all the treasure vaults.
Even if he's never met you,
it's child's play for him to
read your actions and thoughts.
That's impossible.
No, we're talking about Thousand Tricks.
The pub incident was also all calculated.
Every single thing has been premeditated.
Even us coming here.
Don't worry.
Master is aware of all these conditions.
No matter what happens, it's all
according to his calculations.
He would never arbitrarily send
us on an impossible mission.
I assigned that job to her
completely arbitrarily.
I'm gonna puke.
I really hope they'll come
back if it gets too hard,
but I know Tino is under the
bad influence of our members,
so she won't give up that easily.
Even if I wanted to call for backup,
nobody would move out at this hour.
I have to get going.
That's it!
If I hurry, I can stop them before
they reach the treasure vault!
I'll tell them there's been a
mistake and get them to stop.
I'll just get Ark or someone
else to do the mission later.
Right, I got this!
A phantom!
But it's got a sword and armor!
This was supposed to be a regular wolf!
Master...
He always goes beyond my expectations.
I need relics! Relics! Relics!
As many Shooting and
Safety Rings as I can carry!
I need the Owl's Eye,
and this and that and, and...
Huh?
What are you doing with all that?
Eva...
N-Nothing.
I was just thinking of
going on a little walk.
Even if it's a fully calculated trial,
you're still worried about them.
Wh-Whatever do you mean?
Don't tell me that's...
Sitri's Slime!
Y-You wound me.
As if I would ever be in possession of
something that violates imperial law.
All the relics that I could use
for offense are out of mana.
I need to at least take it as a last resort.
I'm off, then. On that walk.
Are you sure you don't need
to take anyone with you?
It's fine.
Even if I did, this relic
only works on one person.
I believe that's the relic...
from the human missile incident.
Zero safeties,
no brakes,
it can't hover or steer...
It's plain defective.
Night Hiker
Night Hiker!
I wonder if he'll be okay.
A truly dangerous Spartan trial!
Tino's ad-hoc party goes
to meet their destiny.
Krai Andrey, we're counting on you!
Will he reach them unscathed?!
Please tune in next time to find out!
By: Eva Renfied & Tino Shade
He was gone in the blink of an eye.
What speed! Truly Mach!
Hurry up, Master!
Team Tino is in deep trouble
over at the White Wolf's Den!
Our wall spaghetti party is
getting completely swarmed
by the phantoms that just keep pouring out!
These Thousand Trials are so tough!
It does look very bad.
Next time on Let This Grieving Soul...
...Retire!
Episode 03
I Want to Fly Straight Through the Sky
"I Want to Fly Straight Through the Sky."